[Music]
[Applause]
all righty sup y'all it's your boy Rhino
Raider running the Pod solo this week
and when I'm solo you know what we do we
get in those technical nitty-gritty
details um so I actually know what I'm
going to call this episode already I'm
going to call it the saml ramble because
I'm about to ramble for the next you
know however many minutes about saml to
you guys and try to peque your interest
in samel um it's kind of a complicated
topic so um the goal for this episode is
going to get you interested in it and
get you comfortable enough with a
structure of saml where you can desire
to attack it where you'll be curious and
not scared by it whenever you see it in
an SSO context okay so that's the that's
the goal
now um I chose saml because I'm really
interested in it and uh the reason I'm
really interested in it is
this samle is everywhere we see it in a
lot of organizations being used uh for
single sign on and for IDP um your
identity provider uh services and here's
the crazy part okay it's XML based and
which we all know all the concerns that
go around with XML but it just kind of
recently struck me that if a if a
company is using samle for their
identity you know in conjunction with
their identity provider then all of the
different applications that they're
going to be um logging into using this
single sign on will need to be parsing
XML and parsing saml right um and
because it's such a complicated thing uh
you know all of these different
languages you've got Java apps you you
got node apps you've got python apps all
of these are going to have different
libraries that they're using to parse
the saml uh the samel assertions or the
S
responses and um I'm sure that there
will be uh you know some some quirks
between all of these different
applications right so whenever I I feel
like whenever I see saml it's like ah
there's got to be a bug on this scope
somewhere because not all of these
things can be parsing it exactly the
same way okay so rant over there um lots
of attack potential uh for samel so
let's let's get ourselves comfortable
with it because I I don't know about
y'all but before um before I did this
deep dive on saml and prep for this
episode I was a little intimidated by
saml because um you know you see this
giant b64 blob and then you b64 decod it
and then XML inflated so you're actually
looking at the XML and then it's just a
huge you know blob of XML there's all
sorts of like references to what is it
W3 .org or something like that where
it's like check out this protocol and
and that sort of thing and the schema
and there's all sorts of attributes and
you know who knows what all of it does
um and and sometimes even there's like
large bas4 encoded blobs inside of the
assal response you know uh encapsulating
certificates and signatures and it's
just like gets overwhelming really
quickly at least that was the experience
that I had before I I deep dived it for
this episode so I'm hoping that we can
delete that and and get us comfortable
with it okay
so the thing that spurred This research
was um a researcher that I'm really a
big fan of named green dog released uh
some of the details that they did on a
talk in at a conference called kakan
which is awesome that's such a great
name for a conference and I mentioned it
on the Pod a couple weeks ago and it's
called how to break samel if I have paws
okay so I was looking through this this
presentation and I was kind of looking
at all the various techniques in there
and that is an amazing present
presentation that we will link uh you
know below so definitely go check that
out because this is going to require a
little bit extra research on your behalf
to become really really you know on top
of of samle stuff um because there's
only so much you can do over a podcast
um and sometimes you just need to see
stuff so uh there's going to be a lot of
resources associated with this episode
that you'll need to go and check out um
so I was reading through this this slide
deck by by green dog also check out his
weird proxy stuff because that's the
name of the repo weird proxies that's
that's really interesting research um
and I and I I stumbled upon this just
absolute Gem of an article by a
researcher named Epi
052 uh which is the same guy that did
foox Buster by the way um on how to hunt
bugs and samle a methodology and this
was from 2019 research from 2019 and
holy moly is a good um there's three
parts they're they're you know very
digestible very readable very simply
written clearly this guy knows what's up
with with samel because you know when
you can take it and you can make it this
simple it rocks so my my plan for the
rest of the day rest of the day rest of
this episode is to is to talk to you
guys about the methodology that he lays
out in that in that um uh uh blog series
that he does and uh just kind of
generally get us familiar with that so
let let's go ahead and go down that path
so before before we get into the attack
Factor stuff we've got to understand a
little bit about uh saml or uh security
assertion markup language okay so here's
the here's the basic context in in which
uh this is used okay so you've got a
user all right we got we got to get some
terms out of the way here first we've
got um a user that's the person that's
wanting to off into an application or a
service provider okay an application you
know let's say you wanted to off into
you know an
organization's uh let's just to say it's
their git lab or something like that
right that would be a service provider
SP service provider um hopefully these
terms will not make this more
complicated uh or or scare away any of
you so just when you hear service
provider think app okay and then we've
also got the identity provider okay
that's the person that's providing the
identity that's going to be your you
know sort of
SSO domain right your your SSO service
provider okay whoa I can't say SSO
service provider your SSO um portal
let's just say that okay and they're the
ones you log into that and then it
throws your off over to your service
provider or your app Okay so we've got
the service provider that's the app
identity provider that's the SSO domain
okay so the basic flow that happens is
this the user wants to authen the
service provider they want to Au into
the app so the service provider says
okay sure I'm going to create this
parameter called samle request that
contains a base 64 encoded
XML document essentially and they're
going to redirect us uh via our browser
uh over to the identity provider okay
the identity provider is going to look
at that SLE request uh look at the XML
inside of it and it's going to say okay
I understand you know I need to Au this
user for whatever service provider uh
now I need to off this user so then we
go ahead and we put our credentials in
to the service
provider excuse me we put our
credentials into the identity provider
and then it will go ahead and create
something called a SLE response okay
okay the samle response uh will contain
a cryptographically signed uh samle
response tag that contains assertions
about who the user is so they're
asserting hey this user is blahy blah
right you can trust that okay and so
that sample response is put into a a
parameter in HTTP uh it could be a query
parameter it could be a post post body
um and then sends it back over to the
service provider or the app okay um and
the app will then look at that SLE
response parse it and Trust uh
cryptographically hopefully
cryptographically check um that that s
response is is valid not tampered with
and then trust the person that the
identity provider said is there and log
them into that account okay so it's a
pretty standard flow when you look at
SSO um based application so that's the
that's the the basic flow let me I'm
going to take a sip of water now
all righty so um let's let's break it
down a little bit further and we'll
start talking about attack vectors okay
um
so before we get any any into the
technical details of what the uh XML
structure looks like I just want to say
that I've noticed a pretty strong
correlation between libraries and
domains that use samle and xss okay
so I I don't know why that is uh maybe
it's an older technology but um whenever
you see an application parsing samle or
a SSO domain that is is utilizing samel
to log users in um then you're going to
want to check that pretty thoroughly for
xss you're going to want to check that
for xss in the um in the samle request
so that first little um information that
is sent from the service provider the
app to the identity provider or the uh
SSO domain right and you're going to
want to inject uh xss related payloads
in there and and I'll give you an
example of this later um and see if they
fire on the identity provider or see if
they fire on the service provider um via
the samle response so if you're
injecting inside of tags in the SLE
response or you're injecting in in
attributes in the SLE response and
sometimes it'll throw an error be like
hey this is an invalid thing H here's
the invalid thing and then they embed
embed the invalid thing in the Dom and
then it triggers it xss so it's a story
you guys are all familiar with I'm not
going to explain how xss works here but
um just know that there is a pretty
strong correlation with saml and xss
okay and then the only other caveat I'll
add to that is that in order to embed
xss payloads inside of attributes and
inside of tags you may need to uh HTML
encode those brackets normally HTML
encoding is our enemy in these scenarios
right if you see it HTML encoded that's
bad but um in order for it to not break
it and for it to parse properly we have
to HTML encode it sometimes and then it
will get reinjected back into the Dom um
HTML decoded and in its full you know
xss Glory so that that's that I'll leave
that there um definitely look at s
related stuff for xss okay so now let's
go and talk about attacks um outlined by
uh ep52 and what kind of uh attacks that
are a little bit more relevant to Sam uh
itself okay so the first attack that
that ep52 has in their description is
test whether or not the SP accept an
assertion without a signature okay this
is known as signature exclusion okay so
as I mentioned before the SLE response
the thing that is coming back from the
identity provider and going to the um
service provider uh that response is a
XML document and uh there are a couple
things that are normally inside this
document for one there is a samle
response uh tag that that tag contains
almost everything else that that'll that
you'll need inside of it okay um it it
also contains a lot of signatures okay
signatures are the things that uh
cryptographically ensure the Integrity
of the saml response okay um and so when
we talk about uh ANP accepting an
assertion without a signature that will
be um you know us simply just removing
the signature tags from the saml uh the
saml document okay so all you have to do
is BAS 640 code XML inflate um and then
take out the signatures re re-encode it
up and send it over to the SP and if
they accept it boom you're in because
you can just modify that assertion to
have to have um anything you want in it
well how do you modify an assertion well
an assertion is exactly kind of what it
sounds like it's asserting that the IDP
or the IDP the um identity provider is
asserting that the user is a specific
person so a lot of times this will
contain attributes saying uh which is
another tag inside of a samle um saying
something along the lines of like uh
user dot you know username or whatever
is Rhiner rator right and and it'll have
a bunch of attributes that the identity
provider wants to convey to the service
provider okay so if we could modify
those assertions uh and those attributes
within the assertions then uh we're
golden right because um we can just
assert that we're anybody uh and the
only way that those assertions are
actually validated for integrity is via
the signature so if we just remove the
signature and send it on through then
we're we're great and there's a report
that we'll cover later on in this uh
episode that where this exactly this
sort of vulnerability happens so um this
is an easy attack vctor you can try
however
um you don't always have access when
you're trying to hack a
company you don't always have access to
a sample uh sample response
right excuse me um so you may need to
take sort of a template SLE response and
just Google you know SLE response
template and send it on through and see
what it says because sometimes it'll say
uh hey you're missing this attribute and
sometimes it'll say hey there's no
signature here what the heck is going on
right um and so in in the scenarios
where it says hey you're missing this
attribute there's a very good chance
that it's actually not checking the
signature and it's just going to uh you
know tell you what kind of attributes
you need in order to log in any account
that you want so definitely try to be
going after um assertions without a
signature uh when you see any SLE
related um end points
okay um the next the next section that
we want to talk about is uh XML
signature wrapping okay and and I'll
before we get into this section I'll
I'll throw a caveat out here okay um
there's a a burp extension called saml
Raider okay this extension is super fire
and uh ep52 talks about it in the um the
blog post and gives a very clear example
on how to execute all of these attacks
um using Sam Raider uh very simply uh so
if you're using if you're using burp
definitely check that out if you're not
using burp uh you might can open burp
for this specific thing because uh it's
it's pretty awesome and I I don't
believe it's a pro extension so uh
anyone should be able to use it with a
community
addition um okay so let's talk about uh
XML signature wrapping in order to
actually understand this vulnerability
from a technical perspective we have to
understand a little bit about signatures
okay um so as we mentioned before
signature the signature tag inside of
the SLE response is the thing that uh
gives
you gives us cryptographic security when
when using samle okay so there's a
couple tags uh inside of the sample tag
that we need to be aware of there's the
signed info tag there's the signature
value there's key info and object okay
um the the most important one here is
signed info and that signed info also
has a subtag called the reference tag
okay and that reference tag is going to
contain a URI attribute just like this
is just like HTML right like you have an
HF attribute for an for an a tag right
um we have a URI attribute for this
reference tag and this is going to
provide an ID of the assertion or the um
other tag could be a response could be
an assertion that uh it is signing for
okay uh so you know let's say you've got
a response that has ID 1 12 3 and then
somewhere you've got a signature that
has a reference with URI equals 123 that
signature is correlated to that response
okay so you just compare the IDS and
you're good to
go um and these signatures can live in
multiple places throughout the XML
document okay there's three that you
need to really be aware of there can be
an enveloped signature which is the
signature inside of the response right
so you've got response tag and then
you've got signature tag um and then
you've got end signature tag and
response tag right um so that would be
an enveloped signature because the
signature is inside of the response or
the thing that it's signing for then
you've also got an enveloping signature
right an enveloping signature and that
is the signature surrounds the response
in this scenario we've got the signature
tag we've got the signed info tag and
then we've got the end signed info tag
we've got the response tag end response
tagged signature right so it goes
signature signed info response and
signature right and so the the response
tag is inside of the um signature tag
itself and we still have the reference
IDs as mentioned before that are
correlating um the IDS of the response
tag with the uh
reference ID inside of the signed info
section of the signature so you know you
should be able to correlate them finally
the last one we've got is the detached
signature okay and this is outside of
the response or the assertion or
whatever it's signing so let's say for
example you've got saml uh samle
response right and then you've got
closed samel response signature and then
closed signature right so it's just
totally disjointed from um the thing
that it's signing okay and because of
these different ways that you can put
this signature there's like a whole mess
I want to say Let me let me pull up the
article right here there's I think
there's eight yeah there's eight
different attacks you can do where
you're like you know having a specific
response that has a detached signature
but that detached signature also has a
you know uh an assertion inside of it
and and like you're just putting all of
these different assertions in different
spots and you're putting um you know
data inside of it in a in a um in an
enveloping signature that is not
correlated at all to this signature and
hope that it will get accepted blindly
um and so there's lots of different
techniques that you can use here to try
to sneak assertions uh and responses
into this this SLE response okay and get
it parsed by and accepted by the service
provider um and like I said before a s
Raider will largely take care of all
this for you um and there's I mean
literally uh each one of the I don't
want to sit here and read all of them to
you because it's just going to be too
dull for a podcast but I mean each one
of these attacks has a beautiful graph
on it um and and will and has like three
sentences associated with it just
explaining what it does right so they
really really simple when you've got the
the graphics um so definitely check out
part two of ep52 SLE testing methodology
if you actually want to understand this
stuff a little bit better but by simply
inserting assertions into various spots
throughout the SLE document you may be
able to sneak some values in there which
could really affect the way that the
service provider parses the SLE document
and maybe even get you a full off bypass
which would be uh super awesome um so
that's that's the uh XML signature
wrapping section the next one on EPO
52's list is test whether or not the SP
verif I that the assertion came from a
trusted IDP okay so is the app verifying
that the assertion is coming from a
trusted uh identity provider right um
and so the way that this would be um e
executed normally is by including a
public key that the SP should use to
validate the the signature inside of the
signature in the key info section okay
um so this is also something you can see
in more detail on the write up but um
just sort of conceptually you're sending
that X5 x509 certificate along with the
samle response um and that will then get
parsed by the SP and used to validate
the the signature on the thing it's like
kind of stupid like why would you use
the certificate of the thing you're
trying to validate to validate it like
that doesn't make any sense um but it
does happen so that's called a
certificate faking vulnerability in SEL
and um and so that's something we should
be on the lookout for and like I said
you know maybe this isn't going to be
vulnerable to one of the applications a
company uses um you know in their in
their infrastructure but if they're
using SLE over the whole organization
then some application has got to be
vulnerable to something right so um
really good ATT tax are uh to Deep dive
here I
think um all right so the next one that
he's got on his list is like test
whether or not the SP creates more than
a single session per assertion okay so
maybe you like take the SP response you
send it multiple times if you get two
unique sessions then you know it's a
replay attack uh you know this one I
just kind of skipped over cuz it's like
H this isn't really a bug um but it
could be indicative of uh other problems
with their samal parsing so you know
maybe poke around at it okay next one is
test whether or not the SP is vulnerable
to xxe now this is the one that I've
been doing for years right whenever I
see samel I'm like all right you know
what
samel Justin's brain goes okay saml
that's XML right uh well XML is
vulnerable to X so let's just try that
um and that's pretty much the extent of
of the SLE testing I did for a long time
um and I found several xxs with this so
definitely do this not trying to
Discount the technique at all but um you
know go and essentially to exploit this
you just have to basic C40 code and XML
inflate the um the uh SLE response and
then uh insert the uh XX payload go
ahead and re-encode it with SLE SLE
deflation and then base 64 encode it um
and then send it over to SP and if they
accept it and it pops then great and I'm
not going to go ahead and explain all
the different ways that you can test xxe
because um you know there's lots of ways
that you could do that uh but I'm going
to leave that as an exercise to you guys
um we will I will say here we will talk
about a little bit later in this episode
about something called uh transforms or
Transformations um which will modify the
XML document uh when it's being parsed
by the service provider and there is a
really cool bug that I'll that will will
link in the description um uh of course
it's project zero because those guys are
total badasses and uh they found a way
to like use transforms to get
past the uh entity um XML entity being
disabled on on a a library and it was
actually only like last year in 2022 so
actually this is something that could be
really applicable to lots of boun
programs still if they're not
patching um so definitely check that out
um all right so check for xxc and I will
add as well you may want to check for
xxc on the service provider side and on
the IDP side right because the IDP is
also you know if it's like One login or
like you know uh some of these other
well-known SSO providers then you know
well I should I shouldn't say that you
shouldn't test those because you
definitely should uh and they most of
them do have bug Bing programs but you
know once you've tested it you you may
not have to test it every single time
you see it um but if it's some janky SSO
provider then you may want to just try
it there too so you can try it on the
service provider side and on the
identity provider side for
xxe okay um the next one on the list is
actually uh uh test whether or not the
SP is vulnerable to ssrf VI certificate
okay and I'm actually I'm going to go
ahead and look at uh the blog post
really quickly here uh yeah okay so this
one actually is not in um EPO 52's um uh
write up this is actually an addition
that I did to to this list um thanks to
to Green dogs um write up and
essentially in his uh in slides he talks
about certificate validation to ssrf
okay and this is something that I just
think is really cool and something that
I've I've tried recently with um with a
couple programs that I have been working
on that accept uh X5 And1 certificates
as input from the user um and
essentially it's some research that came
out in black hat of 2023 so just a
couple months ago
that uh and it was released by a guy
named uh Michael
stenin and uh there's just a couple
Fields inside of an x509 certificate
specifically the extensions of the x509
certificate um that could actually cause
ssrf when the certificate is being
parsed okay so specifically there's a uh
extension called The Authority
information access extension uh I'll
actually just I'll just go ahead and
read it right here
um for instance the authority
information access extension contains a
URL pointing to the issuer certificate
if this extension is used for validation
there's a high chance that you can
exploit it to perform an ssrf attack
okay so there's a field inside of this
um you know extension uh that that you
can put a URL in and when it's
validating that certificate and and
maybe the certificate chain associated
with it then it might reach out to that
UR URL to grab the issuer certificate
right um and so that could result in
ssrf and likely it would be blind ssrf
but uh blind ssrf is better than no ssrf
and blind ssrf can often be well I
shouldn't say often can sometimes be
turned into full read ssrf depending on
the amount of error logging that is in
place so definitely keep that technique
in mind um I think there's a decent
amount of attack surface uh that I've
seen recently um by doing weird stuff
with x509 certificates like um you can
craft a certificate I'm getting a little
bit off topic now but you can craft a
certificate that has some um
cryptographic problems with it right and
when they try to uh use it it will you
know use up a whole mess of of memory um
so I I'll see if I can find that article
and put it in the description as well
but uh definitely be on the lookout for
x509 parsing problems because I think
that is something that we'll see uh grow
uh over the next couple years okay um
next one is test whether or not the SP
is vulnerable to
xslt uh that's extensible Styles sheet
language transformation uh via saml and
to be honest in my samel deep dive that
I did this is the most like mindblowing
thing that I found because I'd heard of
this before actually at one of my first
live hacking events um some Legend I
think it was Sam herb of course because
this is such a like Sam herb thing um
used this to like hack some XML related
thing right uh it might have even been
samle um but uh you know this isn't
something that I had thought about for
years um and and here it is and it's so
much easier than excuse me it's so much
easier than I thought um this is pretty
much very much like a a xxe okay um the
the language xslt is Extreme extremely
flexible uh there's so much you can do
with it um and it's actually if I
remember correctly from the notes I
think it's a turn complete language so
you can write I mean you can write a lot
of code in here um and you can do stuff
like just read files and then ex them to
the attacker server just like an xxe and
actually might even be more powerful
than an xxe in that capacity um so
definitely something cool to look into
here um so let me tell you a little bit
about how it works um I mentioned
Transformations before I'll read a quick
TR uh quote about Transformations uh so
you can understand what kind of role
they play in samle okay so it says
Transformations are a very powerful tool
to transform saml user attribute values
transmitted through the saml response
all right so that's a thing coming back
from the IDP to the SP right to the app
um transmitted through the SLE response
or assertions um from the identity
provider mainly they are used to
transform not changeable values within
the identity provider so the transformed
value fits the uh the required or
desired attribute format in the
application okay so good old you know
identity provider doesn't want to change
service provider doesn't want to change
stuff right here right you know there
has to be this whole language that we've
created just to like make the names line
up so that people don't have to actually
modify their code um and that's what
that's what this is uh and so
essentially how it works is you can add
a transform tag uh inside of your inside
of your signature um which will be par
parsed before the signature is actually
validated okay this is the kind of this
is the crazy thing um let me see if I
can find this other quote here
um yeah the reason for this is that the
xslt transformation occurs before the
digital signature is processed right so
this should really be like setting off
fire alarms in your head right now right
there there is something there's a token
that is being taken and used for
authentication and there is a whole you
know turning complete language that you
may be able to use uh in this the
parsing of this token which uh gets
processed before the cryptographic
signature gets processed right it that I
mean I can feel my I can feel my pulse
Rising right now just just talking about
it right um so very cool stuff here and
something that we should definitely be
looking at anytime we see Sam um because
you know even signature validation isn't
going to stop us here because it gets
parsed before signatures get validated
so uh very cool so
essentially you know I've got a payload
here right in front of me and I'd like
to just sort of read it out to you but
it's going to be kind of hard to to
process so essentially I'll I'll tell
you how it goes um inside of this
transform tag you know you define that
there's going to be a um a stylesheet
that is and you reference the w3.org
transform um spec okay so it knows what
what this is and then inside of that you
have this um template that you define uh
that applies to specific um uh XML tags
you can say all right I only want this
to affect whatever tag you know the if
this was HTML you could say all right I
just wanted to affect the H1 tag or
whatever right and then you can define a
whole set of things to do to that tag
and uh from looking at right here from
the example that is in uh EPO 52's write
up um he essentially just says okay uh
assign a variable file to the value for
Etsy password go ahead and URI encode
that file you can see the power of this
language right here right go ahead it
has you a function for encode to URI um
and then uh concatenate it with the
attacker URL and then go get that URL
right um and so it's like this is such a
powerful language that I didn't know
existed uh so so really blew my mind
when I started learning about it uh I
will add one caveat here and I'm a
little bit hesitant to even point this
out because like clearly EP 52 knows
their stuff super well and I I could be
wrong about this but if it's if I am if
I'm not wrong about it then it's
something that could mess up a lot of
people's testing which is that if you
copy and paste at b52s payload
specifically um uh from the from the
article there the template uh tag that I
mentioned in the beginning
has an attribute called match and it's
set to the value doc by default and it
maybe it's something I don't know about
you know XPath stuff but this seems to
to me that they should only apply to an
attribute called Doc and lots of the
other um uh you know payloads that I've
I've looked up for this uh xslt thing
has a match equals slash in the template
tag okay so that would be matching the
root tag of this whole XML document so
it would always apply right um and so it
could be that you may need to modify
this payload that's mentioned in uh EPO
52's um right up here or I could have
something wrong so if any of you guys
know that's listening or feel like deep
diving the uh the explanation definitely
let me know um if I'm if I'm off on this
one but you may may want to do your
research before you just copy and paste
this payload which is good advice for
any payload to be honest um but yeah in
conclusion super cool thing here if
you're going to take anything uh if you
want to do any XML deep diving it could
be really cool to look at uh extensible
Styles sheet language
transforms uh and it also could be good
to look at Transformations themselves um
there's also a whole section of this
referenced in um on slide 26 of green
dog's presentation that I mentioned
before um where he's talking about all
sorts of different Transformations that
you can do uh and this is just such a
cool thing because they're processed
before the actual um you know parsing of
the signature so really really cool
stuff there definitely check that out
okay I'm G to take a sip of water and
then we're GNA we're going to close this
one
out all righty so the last one that we
wanted to talk about here that's on EPO
52's list is if the targetp is serviced
by an IDP to which you have a legitimate
account on a different SP serviced by
the same IDP test whether or not the
target SP accepts a valid assertion
meant for the valid SP okay so that was
uh a lot of acronyms and stuff in there
but the tldr of this is this is an
attack called token recipient confusion
okay so let's say you have an account on
app a that is serviced by the SSO
provider right can you use the assertion
from App a a in in the same response
used to log into app a on app B right so
it's sort of like a like a token reuse
sort of thing um well really it's a
token recipient problem right a token
because ideally the SP should be looking
at the recipient field of the subject
confirmation data element uh which is a
I'm reading this now which is a child of
the subject element in the SLE response
um to determine whether or not this uh
SLE assertion is is meant for them right
uh as opposed to some other recipient so
if they're not validating this then you
may be able to do some weird stuff by um
pulling a valid uh you know token to and
and like we see this we mentioned a sort
of a similar thing um affecting Tesla a
couple weeks ago found by I want to say
it was Evan um Evan Connelly um and it
you know using this sort of
IDP you know taking a token from here
and using it over there that sort of
thing right so it same sort of thing can
happen with saml um with this token
recipient confusion uh bug here okay so
that wraps up the attack vectors that I
wanted to cover under specifically samle
related attacks um now I just wanted to
close out this episode by uh recovering
some hacker one reports um and of course
my my session died to hacker one so I'm
going to have to like go ahead and put
in my off code right here um before I
can load up the report because the
report that I'm going to cover first is
uh a report by Yours Truly um and it's
an xss like I mentioned before uh and so
let's go ahead and take a look at that
uh once I log
in all right here we go so this was this
is a private program so I can't tell you
who it is uh but it's a pretty textbook
xss uh when it comes to uh accesss plus
saml okay and so the situation was this
there was a service provider or an app
that I wanted to log into and it was
using saml so I took the saml response
that I had from a valid login and uh I
modified some of the um attributes
within that uh within that
saml response values right and actually
I believe I was subbing every single URL
in there for my my callback server so
that I could try to find ssrf which is
also not a bad idea um but
uh one of the responses I got from that
was a a message from the uh service
provider saying hey uh invalid response
uh the response was received at the
current URL of the App instead of at the
uh you know my call back URL right and
so uh and it was serving that up in text
HTML so I was like hm I wonder if I can
you know inject uh some some uh HTML
characters in there and so I went back
and I modified and this is is actually
in the destination um attribute of the
assle response so he was checking that
to confirm um you know who should be
receiving this token kind of like we
talked about earlier with the um with
the destination and the recipient stuff
right so there's multiple areas where
you can check for
that so I went to the destination
attribute of the response uh of the
response tag which is the the parent tag
and uh just sort of inserted a uh a HTML
encoded payload cuz I mentioned before
sometimes you have to put HTML encoding
inside of the that um if you're putting
it uh HTML control characters inside of
an attribute in XML uh you have to
encode those with like Ampersand less
than uh or LT colon right or ersan gt
colon right um so we put those in there
and I submitted the the SLE response
back to the service provider and boom it
reflected into the uh into the response
and I was able to get xss now when you
get xss on a uh an app like this a lot
of times it will result in um account
takeover because you can leverage that
position uh in the samle flow uh in the
off flow to hijack that um that page uh
so and and hijack the user session so um
very impactful stuff here uh definitely
be on the lookout for exsess like I
mentioned and then the last report that
I wanted to cover was the One login
Authentication bypass on WordPress sites
reported by J uh a hacker that reported
this bug in May of 2016 to
Uber um and this is just sort of a
textbook off bypass via saml right he
found this newsroom. uber.com and it was
using One login saml SSO um I I assume
it's a plugin yeah it is it's a plugin
um and this report is is public so you
can go see it it's report number 1361
169 that's 13616 69 um and uh he he
essentially just did what I mentioned
before which was he took a samel
response and he you know sort of like a
a vanilla samal response and he sent it
to that that endpoint and then the
endpoint was like yo bro you're missing
this attribute and he's like okay and so
he puts in that attribute and then he's
like yo you're missing this other
attribute and so he keeps on doing that
until he fills out all the attributes
that he needs and then it's like all
right cool got all the attributes log
you right on in there's not even a a
signature tag in this whole payload that
he mentions here okay um so this is a
textbook example of the first type that
we talked about uh which is the
assertion without a signature okay uh so
definitely know that this does exist out
there uh and like I mentioned when
organizations are using saml they have
to you know there's so many different
apps that are using it to log into it
right um and so there's got to be a bug
somewhere there's got to be uh so
hopefully going you know using that
methodology using that mentality you
guys will go out there and find some SLE
bugs if you do definitely DM me it'd be
super cool to know that you guys found
some SLE bugs because of this episode um
so let me just do a quick review keep an
eye out for the xsss in any sort of SLE
environment uh because for some reason
they're particularly prevalent um
there's the uh assertion without a
signature the sign signature exclusion
bug which you just delete the signature
tags from a uh assem response there's
the XML signature wrapping bugs which
there are eight of them um by placing
the signature in different spots uh
throughout the S response and trying to
trick the application into getting to
trust your assertion even though the
signature uh is not valid for it okay so
there's there's that one there's um
assertion check that the assertion is
coming from a trusted IDP that's the
signature faking bug um there's the re
assertion replay bug which is like kind
of a bug but not really um that you
could check for and if there is it could
indicate sort of a less strict SLE
implementation um there's xx's inside of
saml there's ssrf inside of saml either
by um them hitting some sort of uh URL
from within the saml response directly
uh or bya uh parsing a maliciously
edited x509 certificate um and calling
out to your server to uh to validate the
certificate and I think there's a couple
other things not just the um
not just the authority information
access extension there's a couple places
where you can put the ssrf payload
inside the X5 andon certificate so
definitely check out that uh blog post
that I'll have in the description um
from the GitHub blog by uh Michael
stankin um so there's the the ssrf and
then there's uh the
xslt uh vulnerabilities inside of saml
that we spent a lot of time talking
about definitely research these super
exciting stuff here could really result
in some crazy bugs um and then finally
there's the uh token recipient confusion
bug which um you know would be kind of a
specific scenario you need to have this
happen but if you do it still could
result in off bypass so definitely
definitely some really interesting bug
types here all right I think that's it
hopefully you guys have learned some
stuff about uh samle and and uh if you
yeah if you find anything like I said
let me know hopefully you're feeling a
little bit more confident going into
your SLE testing all right go find some
bugs
[Music]